[Music]
do
hello everyone welcome to number three
the third episode in our github star
series and today i have the awesome
gina with us and gina has got
an amazing open source project that she
works on full time and so you know
enough for me
i'm gonna let gina introduce herself and
we can hear more about
her journey her adventures and and what
she's the amazing stuff she's
achieving and what she's got planned for
the rest of the year so gina please tell
us about yourself
well thank you eddie first of all thanks
for uh letting me be here
uh yeah my name is gina hoisker that's a
bit of a tricky name for a lot of people
who
did not grow up in germany and
i am the creator and maintainer of
a little nifty project called octoprint
which is like
remote monitoring slash baby monitor
solution for
uh 3d printers which people can just
install on the little raspberry pi or
something like that and attach to the 3d
printer and then have it
enhanced by with a with a web interface
which they can monitor everything about
which they can send
jobs to install plug-ins and all that
stuff
and yeah that's me that sounds
awesome i want to know more about that
but i suppose before we get to that
so how did you get into tech like when
did you start was it uni was it before
after uh way way before actually so
um i i was always a bit of a weird child
i think
because at h3 i already wanted like a
huge heavy drill hammer and all that but
um around when i was six or seven or so
my parents got
uh um the first computer of the
household which back then was an apple
two e
and uh i wanted to play with that but my
dad told me
yeah well you know that that is more
like a tool not another plate
no no not a toy and uh but i can tell
you i
can show you something awesome and so he
introduced me to basic
uh i could not speak a word of english
back then and everything in basic is
english so that was a bit weird but
um yeah but he he he showed me some
basic commands and
yeah instead of the the more like um
traditional hello world in my case it
was uh the name of a
very popular children's tv show in
germany that was
running in an endless loop on the screen
after a couple of minutes and that was
how yeah basically that was la the first
sight um
and ever since then i have been coding
um and yeah i've always been
interested in tech stuff and and
figuring out how stuff works how things
work i
always disassembled everything that i
got my hands on as a child and
so that was i think a natural segue so
to speak
um and what i also absolutely loved
and still actually do love and and to
this they do is build lego
and uh computer programming is a bit
like building with lego but without you
ever running out of bricks in my opinion
so that was
also like a natural um fit for me
so that this is how i got started i like
the way you explained that
coding is like lego but it's like it's
digital you never run out of bricks
love that i'm so gonna and you can even
yeah and you can even build your own
bricks i mean if you we need one that
has a specific shape
right you can just you don't have to
wait for lego to produce it you just do
it yourself
love that that is right it's building
blocks i really like that we used like
you know
other libraries packages to help us do
it we can write our own as well
which i think is is awesome so let's
hear more about
um i love your open source project i
think it's awesome like it's in
you know in the 3d you know printing
space which is just
so exciting so awesome and how did you
come about with this idea was it one of
those situations where it was
you know scratch your own itch did you
have like do you see something missing
and you built something for yourself and
then it just kind of
grew from there exactly that so i got
myself my first 3d printer back in
i think november 2012 uh
2012. yeah 2012. uh and
it was sitting right here next to me in
my office
and uh well back then printers do not
necessarily have their own memory or
anything on it
uh like they do these days where you can
at least plug an sd card in and print
from that but
you still had to have a tethered to your
to your computer
and stream all the the commands to it
and all that and that was
somewhat annoying when you were also
trying to use the computer for something
else like playing a game or
work or whatnot and also for hours on
end that thing would sit next to me
and produce noises and fumes which also
i mean they are not that bad but if they
do it for hours and hours and hours they
can just go on your nerves
and yeah so there was a point where i
figured okay then
there needs to be some kind of solution
for this problem i cannot be the only
one who has ever experienced that
and so i i i started looking around the
raspberry pi just come out in that year
and i looked for something that i could
just run on a pie and
put the pie on the on the printer and
and plug in the wi-fi dongle back then
the pi did not come with wi-fi on board
and be able to remotely monitor it and
remote control it and all that and it
turned out there was
simply no such thing yet um there were
some projects which treated the printer
like a black box where you would just
push code there and hope it would get
printed but you did not know
if it actually was doing anything there
was no back channel so to speak and that
was something that did not work for me
at all so
yeah um i was still employed with a big
uh yeah i t custom solution development
corporation kind of thing back then
so i was a coder
or rather a software architect by day
and so it came somewhat naturally to me
to also
take the opportunity to start up a new
pet project because it had been a while
since i last had something like this and
at work they did not let me that close
to code anymore because i was too
expensive or something
and so over the course of my christmas
break i sat down
and wrote up the very very very very
first version of octoprint which back
then was
called i think it even was called cura
web ui at first because it was forked
off another project
that in other soic could you reuse the
communication layer because i had no
idea about printer communication back
then
and um so i just plugged this on top
and it worked somehow and then people
complained that they had to install
all of cura in order to run that thing
that i built so extracted it
and then it took off from there
so i i i believe so after the
after the end of my christmas vacation i
figured okay it's doing everything that
i wanted to do now
i'm done with this and just
went back to my regular job and suddenly
i started getting emails and and issues
and all that from all over the world and
can you make it do that and can you make
it also do that and hey by the way i
have this other kind of printer with
this different kind of firmware
and it does this and this differently
and can we maybe make it work with your
thing as well and
around that time that was when i
realized okay
apparently other people do have the same
problems as i do
and i need to maybe
think about how to make this better
so it works for everyone and not just me
and
yeah that was also when it got an actual
name and all that
and what which when you said you did
over the the holiday season
what um which holiday season was that
like how many years ago
2012. oh it was back then okay
so okay yeah yeah so so i it started
over eight years ago
nice and i think i i did the first
public post about
it on uh december 25th 2012.
got you and um what what technology did
you use what was it written in
python yeah so um initially i took a
look at node.js but back then at least i
don't know if things are different these
days but back then
uh the the um ecosystem simply wasn't
there yet
especially not if you were trying to
stay platform compatible
across platform compatible which was
also gold that i had because
maybe not everyone wants to run it on a
raspberry pi but on an old laptop or
something so
and i also wanted to be able to develop
it on my
workstation which to this day still runs
windows
because i also am a gamer and i do not
want to constantly reboot
just to work or game and
um yeah so so i did
so i decided on python and cura was also
written in python so i could just
use these parts that i uh still
have the communication layer built on
these days
and go from there and i had learned
python a couple years ago
before that when i was so i started
right after universe so maybe i should
go a bit back so
uh after i realized hey coding is like
lego bricks without running out of
bricks i decided
uh i need to do this somehow in my life
then i learned software engineer is an
actual job that people can do and from
that
point on so maybe like when i was 12 or
so i was
dead set on becoming a software engineer
so
university was a natural thing to do
right after
graduating from school and so i studied
so
a software engineer or computer science
rather and right after that
i figured i i wasn't really sure yet
what to do next with my life
and a position opened up at the
university to be a system administrator
and so i did that and this is where i
learned python properly
because uh yeah for system
administration for automating some stuff
it can be quite
nice to have and yeah this is basically
what i then um
was able to build upon with uh when when
octoprints started or happened or
whatever
and um when did you go full time on
turrets when did you leave your job and
go full time to it
so that was a bit of a process um
because
so things exploded right and around uh
yeah let's say at the start of 20 at the
middle of 2013 or so it was it got quite
clear that
i could not do this completely just in
my free time anymore because the project
was just too big and the user base was
too big and all that
and so i first talked my employer into
giving me
one day off so i reduced my contract to
at 80 pay obviously and uh
got them to uh make it make sure that i
at least could dedicate mondays as well
to the project
uh so it went like that until the early
uh months i think february or march or
so of 2014 when i realized okay
this one day per week this is not really
enough anymore
and i need to find a way to either
work full time on this or i
have to drop this because at this point
it was become becoming quite unhealthy
and
really not sustainable all evenings were
spent on the project or weekends were
spent on the project
most of the vacation days my friends and
family were a bit of a bit pissed at me
at this point as well so
um and i also noticed it in my health
that i was simply not getting the rest
that i needed because i was constantly
just
either coding on work coding or working
at work on on stuff or
working on octoprint and just at that
time uh suddenly an email found its way
into my inbox from a company
a spanish 3d printer company who offered
to hire me full time to work on
octoprint because they
they basically said hey we like what
you're doing uh we want
want to invite you here uh to visit us
and and let's talk maybe
if you want to get on board with us and
work full-time on octoprint
so i said i immediately got on a plane
to madrid
and we talked and we came to a
conclusion
and this is how i turned it full-time in
august
2014. then said company sadly ran
into some let's call it economical
difficulties
in uh in early 2016
and that was when i suddenly found
myself with
a full-time open source project on my
hand but no
funding right okay that's quite
challenging
yep and this was the point where i
figured okay uh
i am deadly afraid of this whole
situation because
up on this up up until this point i
had always been in a regular employment
situation right so
i had a contract and salary and all that
and social security security insurances
all the all the nine yards of regular
german
work life and
now i had the option of either letting
octoprint go
and going back into something like that
by finding another job which i was
fairly sure i would quickly find
given my uh cv or
and i was quite sure if i did not try
that i would kick myself for the rest of
the
of my life try if i could somehow make
it work through crowdfunding
okay and that was when i turned to
patreon
and fired up a campaign and
rallied people to basically yeah put
their money where their mouth is because
the project was in crisis and it was
either that supporting me
somehow or i had to give up on that
and yeah
to my utter surprise it worked so
people did in fact uh immediately jump
on this campaign and contributed
and uh yeah that was quite it was quite
the awesome experience and to this day
i cannot really i cannot really grasp it
really to this day
like there are thousands of people now
who
give as little as a dollar per month or
as much as 20
and and simply make it work so that
the whole mass of of of people together
makes it so that i can do this full time
and uh can do this now full time in this
mode for
over four years now and this is just
amazing
it's stressful and it's it's insane and
but
but it's amazing that's so cool and
you answered my question already i was
going to ask what sort of donations do
you get are they around the
you know the one to twenty or they in
the hundreds or thousands so
um it sounds like you go for like small
donation donations but a bigger amount
of people
yeah yeah in general it's like i mean
there are some i have two
two legs basically on which i'm standing
uh donation-wise one side is the
recurring ones where patreon wire github
sponsoring by a
um donor box and libera pay
okay and those are like smaller things
but there's also one time donations and
those sometimes are a bit
bigger it always depends so like i do
not make rules there
people give me how many they want how
much they can and they want
and i'm i'm grateful for everything be
it
one dollar or be it obviously more than
one dollar
that's uh i mean that's it's just
awesome i know a lot of people i'm
seeing from the chat now i know a lot of
people
you know want to get into open source
full-time um i know
that i do a lot of open source as well
and people know my stories i'm not going
to go into that
but it's interesting that you know you
you've done yours
via patreon and similar platforms and
that's worked out
really well and you've been going strong
and do you find that as time goes on
it is uh getting stronger as well as in
uh
our other donation are other nations
overall kind of
increasing that in the future you might
be able to potentially hire someone else
to to help you as well is that a
possibility
it's hard to say to be honest so i'm
hoping that someday this is something
that
will be possible though in in germany
there's a lot of red tape associated
with actually hiring someone a lot more
than in other countries
uh which makes this a bit more tricky uh
to pull off but
i hope that maybe someday it will get
there it is
fluctuating so okay
right now it's at a point i would say
where i'm keeping up with uh
with uh inflation and all that but uh
it's always a bit tricky i i alway i
also have
started to to try to yeah
basic basically diversify so that's not
just donations i'm also
using ad revenue i uh use uh
sponsorships by corporations now as well
um and also stuff like merchandise
sales though that is like really really
little
amount but still this is stuff that i uh
also have started doing and yeah the
idea is basically
the shock of of losing this this this
gig that i had that allowed me to do it
full-time because one company couldn't
afford it anymore has taught me that
i think if you want this to work in some
way in open source you really need to
diversify
you need to spread it as far and wide as
possible across as many sources as
possible so that if one
cannot do it anymore be it a one dollar
person or be it a one thousand dollar
corporation
it might still hurt but it will not hurt
as much it will not put the project at
risk that's very true
and we've got a question here from
santosh another github star who was on
my channel i think last week or the week
before
um so if i can maybe generalize this
question a bit
i guess from your different sources of
income what's the percentage that you
kind of that it makes up your income so
i'm guessing patreon makes up the
biggest chunk that you get yeah yep
definitely
and then the smallest chunk is is that
getting to be the the swag sales
yeah yeah that that would be that i
guess
the rest is like in between okay
why does github sponsors i guess sit in
in that scale roughly
um is it catching up with patreon or not
really
oh it's far away like it's moment it's
currently like at uh
um how do you say like a tenth maybe
of uh okay off of patreon
uh but obviously i mean patreon has been
there longer as well and this was also
the platform that i started on
and uh yeah um
it's just spread across it but but from
the
from the one time from the recurring
donation platforms one
github sponsor i think is the second
rank right now for me
okay okay that sounds with regards to
what i get back from it yeah
that sounds good and uh here's a
question from five iv let me bring it up
on the screen
how often does full time open source
become economically viable is it better
to do half and half
or work in paid rolls for a few years
and then full time open source while
using save money
it's tricky i think to be make it become
economically viable so in my case i
think i just had a perfect storm of
having a
committed community already who had said
who i had been able to
to show that i can deliver and that i
can do a good job
and uh that i think enabled this to work
mostly but i cannot really
say what is the best approach here what
i
what i would advise against from a
sustainability and personal health
kind of a position is actually to try to
do it
at the same time both i mean
what what what i think is important if
you do open source and you do not
do it yet full time then make extra
extra sure that you do not
overwork yourself because the last thing
you want is to i mean
we do open source at the beginning at
least and
i personally still do it for fun right
because we like growing with it
and we like helping people and we like
learning new stuff and we like
solving problems maybe and playing with
lego bricks that never run out
and um so when you
do that and but you also have to run a
day job
it can start to feel like a second job
and
it can stop being fun and it can start
to
quickly dissolve in or evolve into into
burnout territory and this is something
that you have to be really really
careful of
so yeah the last thing you want is
something that you love to be actually
something you start hating
that's so very true it's very true it is
hard work at the beginning i think it's
just finding that balance so you want to
work
hard so you can keep pushing forward but
like you said not work too hard where
you burn out and then you start to
to hate it as well yeah i think you
should just not try to force it
because i mean i'm very very much aware
that what the the situation that i find
myself in that
that was like a one of uh one of one of
a kind situation like
being able to start out funded by a
corporation being able to
grow the project during that and then
switching to crowdfunding and i'm not
sure if i had been able to pull this off
if i hadn't had this
this almost two years of being able to
already work on it full time
in a in a financially secure setting um
and and proving my worth so to speak and
also
laying some ground work that then i
could
more easily build up on after
so yeah okay so uh
next question is quite an interesting
one from uh i think it's alex
says um how do you see the future of
open source i know everyone knows my
answer to this
so i think it's probably uh better for
for you to go first
how do i see it or how do i hope to see
it
both i suppose let's do both yeah
realistically
yeah i mean what maybe maybe something
in the middle of it so what i really
hope is that
uh wait i have to quickly uh fight with
my
earpiece again uh what i really hope uh
happening
or hope to see happening soon rather
than later is this
this this concept of funding open source
becoming more mainstream
because right now most people who use
open source tools and
this also includes people who use open
source tools in a commercial setting
like people working a company building
stuff
up on open source tools they rarely seem
to think about
how open source gets created and this it
just does not fall
from the heavens or something like that
it gets created by people and people
need to
eat and people need to live uh and they
need a roof above their head and they
need a bed to sleep in and they also
need hardware to
develop that stuff on so um
this is something that a lot of people
are still either
ignoring or simply not thinking about
and i hope that this
may be change maybe changes in the
future and
that hopefully people also with stuff
like github sponsors and patreon and all
that becoming more visible
in the community um people will become
more aware that
in order for open source to move forward
and to for projects to actually get to a
point where they
are like at a professional level and and
and and
can it can actually stay at a certain
level of quality so that they
also can constantly be considered for
commercial work and all that
yeah that they should be funded and we
cannot just
always um hope that these people will
get hired by some company
because a maybe they do not want to get
hired by one single company because that
also puts you in weird positions that
i've been in myself
where your company says your your focus
should be this feature
but your user base says but your focus
actually should be that other feature
and then you're the maintainer in the
middle and are torn between the two and
i like okay i do not know what i should
be working on now
um so instead of this it
i think it would be nice if we could
achieve something like this situation
where open source developers can
actually live from what they do
just by them doing it so from donations
from sponsorships and all that and not
by having to rely on being employed
somewhere
or having to sell support contracts
additionally or something because
if you are already if you already need
100 of your time working on an open
source project in order to maintain it
and
improve it and all that um then you
cannot
where should you find the time to also
squeeze in paid work then right so
this is yeah i agree it is hard to
go back to that balance again as well
and i think a lot of companies that
make big money from using open source to
build their project
they don't fund a single kind of cent or
penny or
or what is it in euros is it sense i
don't know but i'm supposed to mount
it we also have sense okay okay cool um
and they don't they don't even think
about that they just think well this is
just
a product that probably a big company is
who's got loads of money like microsoft
google they can do this for free it's
fine yeah
i might see that i even get that with
octoprint really
so i i yeah i get a lot of people who
are like
yeah the team of octoprint all these
guys
and also people think octoprint is done
by i don't know how many people
20 or so all of which obviously are only
male
of course or even like a whole company
and then when people learn
um wait it's primarily me
also i'm female hi they are like what
so yeah that a lot of people just don't
think about it i think and they just
don't
try to figure out who even makes their
the the projects that they run
which is kind of ever since i found
myself in this situation i've started
actually trying to figure out who
makes the projects that i use so that's
been an
educated educational experience as well
i have to say
yeah i think i think it's the people who
do the hands-on are going to have more
of an appreciation for the other open
source projects that they use
but the people who hold the purse
strings in the company are never going
to look down at the details
of um of the products that are being
used they don't they don't
kind of care what pit package or npm
package is being used and should
should they fund you know should they
donate to those projects and i think
that's something that hopefully in the
future
can uh can change i hope so too
i think it would it would lead to quite
a boom in open source i mean
the whole internet is built on open
source uh our smartphones
are primarily built on open source
you would think that at this point there
would be
like a better business model than hoping
that people give you money out of their
out of the bottom of their hearts
basically um so and it's the people that
give the money and not the people that
are
you know the big players in the
companies that probably haven't had
money yeah i find quite interesting it's
people who are
you know in the tech and and so forth
who are sharing their hard-earned money
exactly
the people who have earning hundreds of
thousands a year they're not interested
they don't care it's kind of
below them not in a bad way but it's
just something they don't kind of care
about
um yeah yeah hopefully that's something
we can we can all
change and improve on so
oh was i pressed damn it eddie you broke
it
no nobody look never look okay i fixed
it i fixed it yeah you'll find it okay
i pressed the wrong button on the stream
deck gotta get used to my new
back to being into my new office uh
let's have a have a look um actually
before we go on to this question i just
want to say one one thing
um this is one thing that when people
say hey eddie i'd love to donate you
donate to you on github sponsors and
sometimes i ask this and or if they say
it they'll say i'm gonna donate five
dollars to you one thing i do say is i
i really appreciate that thank you so
much but if you can donate five dollars
maybe just give me one dollar and donate
the other four to four other people in
the open source
um community and i i because for me one
dollar and five dollars yes there's a
five times value difference
but i don't know i'd love other people
to get that because just that one dollar
still gives me the motivation to kind of
you know do more and keep going
even when people share things on social
they don't know about you but i love it
when
when if someone took a screenshot of
this and shared it on socials
i'm going to give it a like for sure but
if they add some value that something
they learned like if they said i love
this this tip that gina gave is
something i want to work towards or
something like that
then i'm going to retweet that because
then they're adding it's a bit like open
source
they're adding value to the conversation
no hint there everyone to screenshot
this and share something that you like
uh okay sorry so back to this so
privatization of
ai invite in open source i don't know
much about this area i'm not sure about
you
me neither sorry okay we'll have to uh
have to move on um
if anyone has any thoughts on that do
share it in the in the chat do answer
each other's questions in the chat
because it is quite interesting
and while you're there give this video a
thumbs up and subscribe if you haven't
already
and gina's details are in the
description below so you can go follow
on socials and and so forth and
find out what exciting stuff is going on
uh let's have a look what else have we
got in the chat hopefully i haven't
missed too many questions if i have copy
and paste them
again uh here's a question uh
by five ivy which is quite interesting
is quite a kind of a general
open source question uh about security
should people um find out about what
software they're using from a security
perspective
oh definitely definitely and i'm
actually kind of shocked
that so many companies aren't so
um i mean i should probably not
complain too loudly about that because i
also i mean i look at the stuff that i
use but i do not
look completely down the dependency tree
on everything right
and that can be quite long it's not as
bad in python as it is in the npm
ecosystem i gotta say
so uh whenever i look into the
dependency folders there
it's like thousands of packages that's a
bit insane but
um yeah so that is really something that
people should
be looking at and should also i mean
my personal opinion is if i am a company
and i fund my
company somehow or my build my company
somehow on open source
shouldn't i as a company have a very
very deeply ingrained interest in this
open source projects
to continue to be maintained and to
get fixes and to see security fixes
also and also maybe to see new features
and all that
because that would be my logic
where i in this position as for example
as
a cto or something um because
building my company on something that i
do not control in any way
not even in this in the tiny tiny way
where i shove
money in its general direction is a bit
i don't know not really
careful not really good planning like
very risky yeah i think a lot of people
don't worry about things until they
start something breaks or screams and
and so on i see a lot of companies don't
worry about like automated testing don't
worry about
you know penetration testing or
accessibility until something goes wrong
and by then it's
it's too late anyway yeah
the same goes for a library that no
longer gets
not no longer sees updates right i mean
we don't do not even have to look at
security for that
to be painful possibly
true um i had a question i've just
forgotten oh yes github stars so
i know people always ask me how i became
a github star and my thoughts and
they've heard me share this like 100
times
so i'd love to hear it uh you know the
story of
how it became about and i don't know
anything else you want to share on that
really
i'm not really sure if there is big that
big of a story to it because
i just suddenly found uh an invite in my
in my in my email box and was like
huh what is that some kind of new
program that i haven't heard about and
then i took a look at it and i
was like okay that sounds interesting
because um not only is it
kind of appreciation for yourself that
you know apparently what you're doing
means and matters in a way that it gets
recognized
uh by a company like github but it also
gives
me basically a back channel to people
that uh or whose product and whose
platform i daily interact with
so that has been really really nice on
both both
both sides and um yeah so when i
when i got the invite i was like oh that
would be awesome
and then i actually got the confirmation
and the day the confirmation arrived
that i was now a github star i was like
i'm still waiting for my care package
because some stuff got delayed but yeah
but it's okay i mean
things go as they are you can watch a
youtube video on me unboxing mine if you
want i mean that i thought that was
yeah i i i i was i was actually thinking
about that but then figured uh maybe i
will just maybe that will make the
weight harder you know you will that's
what i was saying
so so i'm i'm going to just wait a bit
uh longer
on whenever it arrives i'm also still
waiting for my um
github community star award thing what
okay actually no i'm maybe i'm waiting
for that one as well
i think you you probably are as well i
think they are getting printed at the
same time or something
yes yeah that's the the 3d printing of
our green bars right
i know the other one the one that we got
at the norway
there's so many so much swag they're
sending us i lose track every every day
i wake up
has arrived i only have got two so far
but
right but they were awesome i mean i
mean the light is from from from them
and their mic is from them and the pop
filters from them
so sure and the water bottle you got the
water bottle right
was that the water i also got the water
bottle he did so so i gotta say i
i really love mine that i already have
so
awesome but i have it and i i like i
like having stuff that is awesome
yeah and then you're hanging out with
the other github stars and being in the
in the github slack and nova conference
and help each other on the slack that's
also really nice i found so like
i have this problem does someone have an
idea yeah try this oh it works thank you
so this is really awesome exactly and i
know i wouldn't have met you really
because
i don't i don't i'm not in the the 3d
printing space so for me i wouldn't
you have discovered you and same with
the other people we've got you know
santos in in the chat actually i
probably
would i knew about santosh i think
before because of the whole angular
space
um so yeah it has worked really well and
hopefully we can encourage people to
um you know help more in the community
so they can potentially become a github
star in the future
i think a lot of people think you've got
to promote
github i know i do but i don't think you
or others do
you use github but you don't you don't
promote it it's not what you do
and i think other people then hopefully
can be made aware that it's just adding
value i think to the community and open
source
which is what puts you on github's radar
to become a
potentially a github star at least that
is my
impression definitely as well i mean i
do obviously when i use
tooling provided by github for example
when i do stuff with github actions or
so i i talk about it because
for me personally it's the right choice
and i just want to help people
utilize it as well but that for me this
does not qualify as promoting that's
more like
hey for me this worked maybe it works
for you as well
if not then no problem so
that makes sense okay we've got some
more questions coming in so i'm getting
a bit behind so i want to bring these up
so
i'm not contributing to bigger projects
and if i see myself as a potential
employee
don't think any recruiter would be
impressed by any kind of my quality of
contributions any tips
a recruiter that actually looks at open
source contributions i
think will not really care about whether
the project is big but rather whether
the contribution
makes sense and adds value so i would
not worry about that too much personally
i mean i would do that if i was a
recruiter i would not look at
did this person contribute to i don't
know this big note library
or did they maybe just create a single
tiny tool that solves one specific
tiny problem but solves it well
or maybe they contributed a bug fix to a
tiny tool that's also problem so i think
this is
it's it's it's more important i think to
contribute value than what project you
contribute that value to
at least i hope this is also how
recruiters see it
um if they don't personally i would not
want to work for them
but yeah true i think a lot of
recruiters just look at
is your profile busy lots of green but
they don't
yeah deeper until i do because i do
recommend to people to have an active
profile with
you know a fair amount of green because
the first impression
and then hopefully later on a hiring
manager is going to dig deeper and
actually
look at the the value added but yeah i
don't think a recruiter is ever going to
dig deeper or understand what a good
issue is or what a good pull request is
or anything like that
um so yeah it is
it is a challenge but i think a lot of
them are becoming more aware of it
though
as in hopefully they'll educate
themselves a bit to at least
look a little bit further into it
i would hope so because i mean getting a
really green
guitar profile is like uh
one cron job away and i mean you can
completely automate that
so it's it's it says absolutely nothing
as long as you do not
actually dig into what these green dots
consist of
and in that moment yeah true but i don't
recommend anyone automating it because
for me when i'm reviewing someone's
profile yes
if it's more green i think it looks more
impressive i'm going to dig deeper but
as soon as i find out something's
automated like that
i discard their entire application
i literally just yeah i would also not
recommend i mean what you can do
you can do that for fun if you just want
to play around with it right
on a throwaway profile if you just want
to figure out how it works
like for experimenting yeah
but in general no i would not do that on
my profile
me neither and i would also not i mean
i would also refrain from doing drive-by
pull requests or something like that
just to have activity
right because this is also if you just
fix a typo somewhere which wasn't
actually a typo or
so like the typical commits that you get
during hacktoberfest when people try to
pad their profiles up so that they can
reach these
so these kind of commits they are not
really actually
those that are not actually adding value
you should not
try to do them i think just to make your
profile more green you should just
add value be yourself and if it's a fit
if
it's a fit and if it's not a fit and
it's not a fit and i don't think it
makes sense to try to be
something or someone you're not just in
order to get hired in some position
where you then will hate it because they
assumed you were someone else and also
you should not force yourself to work or
try to work on big projects which are
already
drowning in contributors anyhow probably
because they are way more high profile
and people think that they can pet
maybe also their cb with that and
instead
there are a lot of low hanging fruits
all over the the open source community
contributing to projects that
desperately need help
and would probably love help in any
shape or form and
yeah just tackling that kind of stuff
would
also help you to have a busy profile and
learn and discover new technologies
and find new friends as well a lot of
i met quite a number of friends during
open source work
and yeah would not make you
feel so stressed all the time yeah i
agree i think a lot of those bigger
projects people want to put on their cv
i contributed to react or whatever they
move so
fast that you get disheartened a lot as
your pr just
ends up with lots of conflicts and you
know you're just kind of you're you're a
smaller
what's the expression you're you're a
smaller kind of
piece of the puzzle i don't know what
the expression is commit
no yeah i think there's nothing to do
with cogs like you're a smaller
cog in the wheel or something i don't
know but like it's you you're you know
yeah yeah yeah requests going on that
yours is just
you know if you contribute to a project
like you said that's moving slower
and that welcomes contributions more and
maybe getting a pull request
like three pull requests a week then
yours are gonna get more attention
whereas when you contribute to a bigger
project that's maybe getting
30 pull requests a day then yours is
going to disappear very quickly maybe
not they get the attention you won't
learn as much a network as much as
you need exactly so it's true
so um i'm not sure if we can we can if
this is a question or not
um the dependency chart of everything as
we mentioned yeah just goes deeper and
deeper
and i think uh as juno was saying you
cannot go all to the nth level of it
i think it's just you would like to
think that you trust
the projects you include and they trust
the projects they include i'm guessing
and so on i'm not sure
if that's a safe bet or not but it's
probably not
um but let's just assume it is so we
cannot sleep at night
that's true and i think the github is
doing a lot of great work with security
and there are other platforms
uh as well yeah definitely
uh this is an interesting question
someone asked me this the other day and
it definitely took me back
so gina what was your first open source
contribution
i think the official first open source
contribution to someone else's project
was
um i was quite have acquired
a crime regular now that that's the word
that i was looking for
was a quite regular um contributor back
in the day
at the dockerwiki project which is like
a wiki engine php
based um this is also how i met one of
my best friends
who is the who's who's the maintainer of
the project and
andreas from whom i learned a lot um
about
maintaining open source projects and and
also yeah i got to meet a couple of
times
so um that was yeah one of the
i think i first started writing plug-ins
for that and then i started pulling
i i wrote my first ever fix for some bug
in the engine itself and
i remember that i was quite um yeah
thrilled about having the patch get
accepted
and yeah so that was fun um and before
that i actually
tried i tried to build something like
dokobiki myself at first before i
came across toku wiki and that was
probably my first
actual open source project with a
license and all that and even before
that so that was like when i was back
when i was still back in school around
yeah the late 90s and the early 2000s
so late late late years at school i i
actually
wrote some stuff that these days i would
consider open source but
they didn't actually have an open source
license so technically they weren't
um but yeah so that
that is a long time ago in a galaxy far
far away and all of that
i think we covered this but let me just
bring it up from five iv
is it bad if a profile is more green due
to ci practices of multiple branches for
every feature
my understanding is only the default
branches count
yeah which is actually something which
is for me quite upsetting because
octoprint's default branch is the stable
branch which only sees merges when
i put out a release so my my own github
profile is fairly misleading most of the
time
because it looks like i'm not doing
anything for weeks and when in fact
i am just not on the main branch yeah
yeah it jumps then it gets filled up
then off
yeah yeah but yeah so
you you cannot you cannot just jump
around between branches and do stuff it
only only stuff to the main branch
actually counts for that thing so
you can do whatever you want with your
ci
on different branches as long as it's
not the main branch it will not look bad
i think
true yeah exactly and i think um some
people get upset when they
um they do a feature that maybe has 10
commits but when it gets merged into the
default branch it gets squashed
people that want clean history right it
is important too
it is important i mean i sometimes do
this as well i guess i gotta admit when
it's like
when when each commit is not actually
yes i know what you're gonna say
telling a whole story but it's more like
uh they they do not work
separate from each other and you have to
actually com
apply them all or none at all in order
for the code to still stay
sensible yeah
uh what else so someone's asking about
github actions
i don't know much any resources well do
you use github actions for your project
you know do you use something else
a ton a ton i just actually rewrote
about
a bot that i use for helping me with the
issue tracker and made it use github
actions
and i wrote my first actions in in in
node as well for that
and yeah it's it's i gotta say i i
currently consider it github actions as
the hammer to
every single nail that i encounter
regarding automation um
in in the project like labeling of prs
automatically based on what files are
touched
and uh yeah i do stuff like that
i do tracking of a labeling of issues
based on certain keywords they contain
i um also validate uh issues
like have people actually included the
bug tracking template for example with a
github action
i also close them if they don't contain
the the issue template after
14 days with the github action done
stale
handling and all that and excessive
testing set up
and i have this whole page build set
up for the plugin repository which is a
static page powered by jekyll which
pulls in dynamic data from the statistic
page
and and all that and then builds it in
all while the github actions so i can
only recommend getting into that stuff
it's fun
like really fun like i enjoy when i i
get to write a new action kind of fun
it is it is really really awesome uh it
is just
because you can write it it just starts
off with there's so many let me start
again i've said try to start three
different sentences
um there's just so many actions in the
marketplace that you can use of just
some
basic yaml lines and then if you want to
customize it further then you can use
you know so many different languages
like you said node or i think python's
all supported i'm not sure but there are
various languages that you can use
you can use node.docker like you can
fire up a dock and then you can use
use whatever uh what i can also
recommend if someone is
trying to get into github actions and is
maybe afraid a bit of
of getting their feet wet completely
already with
note or docker based stuff there is this
fancy little
kind of tool kit which is an action
itself which
is action slash github dash script
and that allows you to just throw a
bunch of javascript into the body of the
action
which then gets executed and i use that
for some labeling actions and that's
like you you completely write that in
yaml
or rather i mean you still write
javascript but you dump it in the yaml
and it's just if you just need a one-off
kind of thing and you cannot really find
something on a marketplace that fits the
bill and it's really easy to
because it's just like two queries
against the github api and then maybe
some logic in between or so then this is
like
i i constantly use this for for for
stuff like that all the time and it's
it's really easy to prototype things
with that as well if you
have an idea how something might work
and maybe we'll put it in a proper
action after for others to reuse but you
first want to test if
if the idea in general works then this
is also great for that
yeah it's uh just uh someone's writing
in the chat that you can use any
language or docker container exactly
it's just
so flexible you can trigger off any
event in github
and there's just so many things you can
do it's it is
so much fun i think people do games with
github action so in their read me they
have like nuts and questions
and and then oh my god okay it raises an
issue
and then the issue will then update that
the board in the readme and then you
click on it and so forth it's quite
quite funny to see
the things that have people have done um
i think
i even see mine sweep which is really
important oh my god
i really need to up my readme game i
think i currently just have a basic list
of hi i'm gina and i'm doing this
thank you for your for your attention
bye-bye um
yeah yeah i think the read me spend so
much time on it though just tweaking it
and
improving it and and so on
we we have a great question here
actually um what are you what are your
thoughts on these i have i have a
thought but i'll let you go first
um if any project doesn't have a license
is it not considered open source
not really not legally no because the
thing is that in order to say something
is open source the source has to know
rather there has to be a license that
actually allows to utilize it in certain
ways
so there is a definition by the open
source initiative
that says what constitutes an open
source license and what must
what it must fulfill and what it must
not fulfill so for example it does
it must not restrict your use of the
software in any way or shape
so it must not say something like you
may use this but only in a
non-commercial setting or so in that
moment it is not
under this definition it is not open
source and
in case of at least something like
germany for example we
have the problem i would not necessarily
call it a problem but when it comes to
open source it is an actual problem
that any kind of created
things like for example source are
automatically copyrighted
so i do not have to apply for copyright
for copyright for something that i
created for it to be
protected under under the law of
copyright in germany
so when i just throw some source up on
github
it is automatically copyrighted under
german law and in theory no one
may use that they may look at it
but they may not use it and they may not
copy it and they definitely may not work
built up upon on it so in order for this
to be legally viable i have to attach a
license to it because otherwise it's
automatically
protected under a very very restrictive
one
so at least i i think in in in the us
and and also in other countries on the
in the world it is probably different
but at least
in germany maybe even in all of europe
i'm not entirely sure but there are
these
very fine points in copyright law that
um make you very very aware once you
actually look into that
into it a bit uh how important it is to
actually attach a license to your source
and not just
throw it up somewhere and be like do
whatever you want with it because do
whatever you want with it is not a
license i think i remember
last time i was reading this um and
again that you're right
i think it's country specific but if you
don't put a license on something you
default to the terms and conditions of
github and so then it then i think it
specifies certain countries and you know
that can't i don't know if it can
override certain country rules or vice
versa
but um it doesn't make it open source so
you're absolutely right
and so uh choose a licensed website by
github has some really good comparisons
and information so
yeah i highly recommend people put a
license on it therefore it is clear and
you can always change the license later
if you want that's my understanding
be careful okay interesting so okay i
actually gave a talk about this whole
topic once
at maker faire in germany um so
the thing is that what i would recommend
is if you want to choose a license for
project
actually read the license yes it's it's
a lot of legalese and it is hard to
understand but
there are tools online that will help
you like tldrlegal.com for example has
all the open source licenses listed and
you can click on them and it will
explain
the basic gist of what is in there like
allows that in that case of use
contains liability or doesn't contain
liability allows resharing or not with
or without attribution and all that and
you can look at that and then you have
to
think long and hard about whether you
actually want to license your work under
that and if you're comfortable
for example if you choose something like
the mit license which basically just
says do whatever you want you just need
to keep this copyright notice intact and
you cannot sue me for any damages that
my code causes
um you when you use this license you
have to be
aware that a company may come take your
code
and build a multi-million dollar a
company off of it or product off of it
and you will get
not a single dime and not even actual
recognition and you need to be aware
that this can happen
i mean the likelihood is very small but
still it can happen and you should be
comfortable with this thought and if
you're not then you need to choose
another license
something maybe that is viral like the
gpl or so where they at least are forced
to publish the sources that they built
on your
on your work on top of your work
because and this is where your former
question comes in
um relicensing of your code can become
quite tricky as long as you are the only
person who wrote it then
there is no problem right okay but as
soon as you want to introduce a license
for example if you want to switch from
mit
to a somewhat more restrictive gpl
because the gpl has this
viral ver virality clause in it
you actually need to ask everyone who
even contributed a single line to your
code
or even a just a single character if
they are okay with that and if they say
no then you have to replace whatever
they contributed
right okay interesting yeah so
this is the reason why octoprint to this
day is still a gpl
licensed because i started off of cura
as i mentioned
cura was licensed agpl so i inherited
the license because it's viral
and these days i actually would prefer
to be able to just switch it over to
something slightly different more like
the lgpl maybe because it would make
more sense in the case of something that
is more like a platform or framework at
this point than
like a network appliance or something
like that for which the agplus moment
but in order to do that i had to i would
i would need to get the legal
permission from every single person who
ever contributed to both
the parts of cura that are still in my
com layer as well
as everyone who ever even put a single
digit somewhere in
in octoprince code and this is like how
many people like hundreds or thousands
yeah yeah i actually do not know right
now how big the network graph is but
it's quite a number of people and
frankly
i do not i do not think that many would
answer
true so i mean even if they would
technically be okay with it
yeah right p try getting people's email
addresses first then trying to get in
touch with them
then trying to get a permission from
them so yeah best
settle on a license that you are
completely 100 comfortable
when you release something because
changing it depending on
how many people have already contributed
can be a big
big pain in the behind
that is true okay i wasn't aware of that
see i learned something new as well
which is great which is why i like
collaborating with so many people and
just chatting to people because you
always learn
you know different things i know we've
covered this already
um just to say that i don't think there
is a best license choose one
that you're comfortable with probably um
i prefer i mean there are a couple of
popular ones
sorry which ones yeah
there are i mean the most common ones
these days are the gpl
the mit and the bsd i would say maybe a
bit of the apache 2 stuff but that's
that depends a bit on the in on the on
the ecosystem you find yourself in i
know apache 2 is quite um
uh quite popular in the java group but
i've seen it less and less in the in the
python
and node.js ecosystem
so yeah and i would just suggest to sit
down and read through the most
common ones i mean on the one side you
have the viral
stuff like the gpl the agpl the lgbl
gpl and on the other side you have the
non-viral stuff
like the mit the bsd the apache 2 and a
bunch of other things
and just yeah go on tldrlegal.com
click through them and just figure out
what the differences are and
what you want for yourself personally
i so small stuff that i primarily
write to quickly fix some kind of
problem that i have and that i
then just throw online don't give a lot
of maintenance for or something more
like i merge prs when they come in and
if there is a big bug and i have an idea
idea of how to fix it i fix it but
otherwise it's not that big of a
priority and more like a pet project
i usually these days license under mit
okay
because it's like a here you have it i
don't really care about it
have fun with it use it if it is useful
for you yay and
if not then well but what are you doing
here um
but for for things that i really care
about like octoprint
i would never even if i had the choice i
would never license octoprint under
something like an mit or bst
bsd license because this this viral
character in this case there is
just too much work on this that i do not
really want
to have to face the situation that i've
now
actually faced a bunch of times with
companies who simply ignored
the license that they put it in some
kind of product of theirs claim it's
theirs
and make a ton of money from it so um
especially considering the fact that i'm
trying to live from the work that i put
in this
right it's like also i think
it's i mean i know this is kind of a
philosophy
philosophical war a bit going on there
between the
between the viral and the non-viral camp
when it comes to open source licenses
but personally i think
if we want to somehow get
companies to actually respect and
and realize that open sources work and
that it doesn't fall from the sky and
that maybe they
need to um they they need to contribute
back to it something like dual licensing
or something would also be an option
like if you are using
my my my stuff in an educational or in a
private setting then
it's licensed under n and under my under
under
under mit and otherwise it's gpl or
something like that or you can
the other way around sorry so you can't
do stuff like you can buy a different
license of course for that you need to
have
everything under your control but yeah
that is a really interesting one
actually i do i do like that having two
licenses you know if you're using it for
a pet project
or for some educational school then fine
you know use it
whereas if you're going to make money
out of this then you've got to either
yeah
you've got some clause you've got to
have you've got to keep your code open
source as well or whatever it is exactly
so i do like that actually that's really
interesting that's something i think i
want to start doing
i'm having dual license i'll have to
look more into that
i've got some people in the chat i did
paste in some examples
about mit and where like ansible bash
and [ __ ]
you sorry uh where is it babel.net core
rails use mit whereas ansible bash
and [ __ ] use uh gpl uh version
3 and then santosh is saying that
angular is mit
so it's always yeah always always quite
interesting
to see what other projects are using
yeah when including other projects in
your projects you need to look at those
as junior was saying because they might
have some restrictions what you can do
with it can you sell it
and and so forth because you might be
able to sell it you need to have open
source
now you also need to be very very
careful when for example
not every not all licenses are
compatible to each other for example you
cannot
um i'm trying to think of a good example
right now but i can't
for the life of me um in theory there
are certain licenses situations
where if i having an having my stuff
licensed under an agpl
would try to utilize this library under
something else which i can think of
right now
then this would not work because the
licenses would
yeah negate each other not negate but
you know like they would have clauses
that conflict without
with with each other so it is very
important that whenever you
work on something that is open source
you actually check if you can include it
for example if you work on something
that is mit i think you cannot
incorporate stuff that is licensed under
the gpl
without re-licensing your own project as
gpl because the viral clause in the gpl
restricts things further so that the mit
right you you you you would give your
stuff away for free
but um so completely for under under
terms of the mit but if you bind against
stuff that is gpl or pull whole code
snippets in that are gpl
you are doing the same to that as well
and this is against this license because
this license says
you may only share it if you share it
alike
so with a gpl or a gpl compatible
license
which i think actually hasn't has an
exception for mit but still
i mean yeah there was a famous story i
can't remember
the the project or the company name but
they had built this open source project
that had done really well for like i
think like seven years
and then they thought you know what we
want to we want to make it a closed
source project because
now it's like it's it's it's done so
well
but obviously by the licensing they
couldn't just do that so they kept this
open source version that the community
can maintain
and then the company took the code and
started the closed source version
and legally it was correct they found a
loophole but oh my god everyone hated
that company forever afterwards after
doing that because literally they just
did it
actually happens actually quite a lot we
also had a case like this in in in the
3d printing space a couple of years ago
when uh when a popular when a popular
piece of
was it the firmware no it was a host
software popular piece
of basically like a compatible competit
competitor of octoprint but a desktop
application
uh went closed source people were like
oh
and it was a bit tricky in this case
because
they kept the they kept the the oldest
old version kept
kept it open source but all the code was
owned by this one person so that the
license
in this case the license which was
completely
legally or fine because i mean if
if all the people that did that that
wrote the code
uh say it's okay to do then it's okay to
do and in this case that the code was
basically built on the shoulders of one
single guy
so that was fine
and this person had to eat so they made
this decision
so sometimes it's okay and
i mean it feels weird and you look at
that in situations like this and are
like
but i mean there's always two sides to a
story
of course i think that's where it goes
back if we go we've almost gone full
circle i'm looking at the clock and
we're gonna have to call it a day soon
but uh full circle to um
that i think i wasn't saying now but
yeah full circle two if companies could
spawn uh could donate or sponsor
um these projects then it becomes less
of an issue and a lot of these companies
you know spend thousands per day on
contractors working on their project
they don't think about the free software
they're getting
where if they just gave kind of a
hundred dollars a month it would just
be and so many of these companies did
that even probably ten dollars a month
which would be a drop in the ocean for
them
then it would just really help open
source move so much faster so many more
people could go
full time on open source and then then
the tools that they're using could then
move so much faster
i think you know there are so many ways
to make money from open source and
sponsorship is just one way but it does
look like it is
that is growing because selling support
like you said
it was always been popular in the past
but it's not great
it's it doesn't scare me scale yeah
exactly
exactly so yeah it's definitely
something to think about and i think
it's going to be
it's going to be interesting uh in the
near future i think
people have become look at github doing
github sponsors right so
now anyone okay some countries aren't
covered yet but
the number is increasing last time i
looked i think it was like mid 30s the
amount of countries that were supported
but anyone can create an account on
github sponsors and people can
give them money i know we have people in
my community that have really helped out
and i say please create a sponsorship
account it's free just to apply for it
and he said but why would i do that
who'd want to give me money i said i'm
i'm hinting to you i want to give you
money
you've been really helpful thank you so
much so um
yeah i think more and more people should
apply for that and go and
add value like you said to projects just
go add value and add value
isn't always just pull requests and and
so forth so
uh yeah that's really interesting i
think it's just been such a great
discussion especially the licenses that
was a
a really a good pleasant surprise but i
think there's a lot of people
a lot of things that sorry it's a
subject that people
shy away from a lot i know i do because
it's just
crazy but it's good that you've done
your research you know about he's gonna
talk on it and
and so on i would link you the talk but
it's in german sadly
yeah my jam is not so good you have to
do an english version
i mean i could do the slice in in
english maybe at some point but
yeah so that was that was quite a good a
nicely filled talk as well i got to say
i was pleasantly surprised by that back
then because i figured if i go
it was it was at the maker faire in
germany so like
lots of people who just build stuff and
are usually not even remotely thinking
about licensing so not software people
primarily but more like
tinkerers and hardware tinkerers and and
people who knit
maybe and stuff like that and i just
figured maybe it would be good
to try to shed some light on this topic
because as an open source dev
like it's it's something that i actually
had to think about and learn about
and at first i was a bit worried when i
handed in this this talk
that the somewhat dry topic would maybe
scare people off but
uh apparently they were actually
interested and happy that someone would
would explain it to them so yeah that
was a nice experience as well
maybe at some point i have to give it
again in english or something i don't
know
i i think so i think it'd be very
popular it is something that people
don't
would like to know more about but don't
want to talk about because they just
don't know
um so i think it'll be really good okay
i think last final question
i think this is quite an interesting one
so apollo thank you so much for the
question
and i don't i'm not sure about if about
this
sorry just to hear what gina thinks i've
had any experience or any stories to
share on this
uh so the question is um
how would someone under 18 uh make money
from open source does it
does it change because they're under 18
i don't know
i'm not entirely sure about for example
github's terms of service but i'm pretty
sure i have to be
of legal age in order to open account
open account
open an account dear and me my tongue is
tricky today probably yeah that's
probably it
um for patreon i think you have to be
uh legal and yeah i could imagine that
this will be tricky because
i i probably i would imagine that a lot
of companies
like github or patreon would probably
like to have you as a creator on board
but
but it would be like a legal minefield
for it
for for them to do it so that makes it
probably a bit tricky
maybe if you had support by a guardian
or
like a parent or someone that's that's
about the only advice that i can give
here because i don't know it's
yeah it is a legal minefield i mean i
see it with
with with stuff like a support forum
only just where you are i
suddenly have to think about stuff like
copper and uh
and and the child protection laws in in
germany and all that and everything
becomes
extremely complicated just because you
have a public forum i do not even want
to think about being a payment provider
or payment service in that case
that is very true they say i don't want
to take up any more of your time i think
i really appreciate you taking the time
out to come and chat to my community and
you bringing some of your community
over because you had a stream just
before us and yeah um
is there anything else you'd like to say
as a closing note or give yourself a
shout out talk about you know give
your project a shout out feel free to
say to do that oh actually just thank
you for the opportunity i had a lot of
fun here
and it's nice to to talk about all
things open source and not just
octoprint for once
but everyone gooch go check out uh
octoprint do have a look at it
and it's been going for quite a few
years and it'll be interesting to see um
yeah how it looks i'm to go check it out
myself after the stream as well
perfect uh thank you so much
no that was okay thank you again so much
everyone will say our buys
um give the video a thumbs up subscribe
if you haven't already check out
uh junior social channels in the links
below i understand one of them's not
working i'm gonna go check this out
after the stream
uh gina hold on for like two minutes i
want to stop the stream and i'm just
gonna thank you again
as well so everyone have a great weekend
remember a green square a day keeps
eddie away so keep contributing adding
value
uh to open source okay let me try to
remember to bring up the holding screen
wait i wanted it i'll move
i like this setup we'll see i like me
being smaller than my guest being big i
think that's um
you know that's pretty pretty cool but
uh lots of people saying thank you in
the chat and uh good night
so that's cool thanks everyone
bye-bye